Finding Aid for the Paul Hardacre Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Paul Hardacre Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS 0669
17.50 linear_feet
Biographical Note
Paul Hardacre was a professor of history at Vanderbilt University from 1948-1985. Born August 25, 1915 in Los Angeles, California, Paul Hardacre did his undergraduate work at Stanford University and earned his M.A. and Ph.D. in History from the University of California, Los Angeles. He was an Assistant Professor at Vanderbilt from 1948-1951, Associate Professor from 1952-1955, Full Professor from 1956-1980, and Professor Emeritus in 1981. Paul Hardacre retired in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The 14 cubic feet collection includes Paul Hardacre’s research materials, teaching materials, correspondence, maps, student papers and dissertations, grade books, and assorted news publications related to the Vanderbilt history department and historical associations. The materials in the collection reflect his specialization in British history. The collection also contains Paul Hardacre’s dissertation The Royalists during the Puritan Revolution, 1642-1660. Student dissertations are listed by student name and located in boxes 11-13.
- London (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Urban History (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Record Publications of Local Authorities (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scottish Societies (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bibliog. of S.E. Thorne (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Wills, Admons, etc. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Survey of Contemporary Materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Student’s Guide to the Materials Relating to English History in the Stuart Period (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Engl. Local Records—JUL Holdings (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Local History: The Parish (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Local History: The Manor (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Local History: Ecclesiastical Courts (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Local History: The County (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Local History: The Borough (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Local History: Visitations (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Anglo-Saxon Chapters (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chronicles (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Domesday Survey (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Medieval Administrative Documents (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Post Conquest Charters (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Parliament Under Edward I. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Commerce & Trade in Medieval England (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Early Christian Humanism (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Early Tudor Government (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Doctrine & Discipline, 1539-1558 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- General Lists of 17th c. books (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Parlt (Box 1, Folder 27)
- .MS. 370.f.b. “A list of the severall Quarters of Sir W. Waller (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Oxford English Dictionary (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Times Literary Supplement: Contributers Index (Box 1, Folder 30)
- B.L. Add. MSS. 21, 417-21, 427 [Adam Baynes Correspondence] (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Hastings MSS. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Add. MS 17, 677: State Correspondence between England & the Netherlands (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Irish Rebellion (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Irish Army (PHH) (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Surrender of Virginia, 1644 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Restoration Army (IREL) (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Commonwealth Navy (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Parliamentary Surveys (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Godwin’s Histort of CMNWLTH (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Tables Illustrating English History (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Documents Illustrative of the Puritan Revolution (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Cromwell, the Earl of Bridgewater & Whitechurch Rectory (Box 1, Folder 43)
- List and Index Society (Box 1, Folder 44)
- International Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Southern Conference on British Studies (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Letters of Recommendation (Colleagues) (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Future of History: Reviews (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Anglo American Associates (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Archives of British History & Culture (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Conference on British Studies, 1981- (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Carolina Symposium on British Studies (Box 1, Folder 52)
- British Studies Intelligencer (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Conference on British Studies, Nominating Committee, 1976-7 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Midwest Conference on British History Studies (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Huntington Early Modern British Seminar (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Inst. of Historical Research: Amer. Friends (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Ford Lectures, (1981) (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Conference on British Studies (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Professional Journals (Box 2, Folder 2)
- William Allen (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Vindiciae Contra Tyrannos (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Historical Abstracts (Box 2, Folder 5)
- CR-14 14 ltrs, 1941-77 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Arkhangel’ sky, S.I., “The sale of Royalist lands”, (1933) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- S.R. Gardiner (see also G.D. notes) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ford Lecture (Oxford) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Clarke Manuscripts (Film) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- S.R. Gardiner (Box 2, Folder 11)
- S.R. Gardiner’s Historical Method (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Marching in Cadence (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Blathwayt (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Beller, Elmer A. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: Genl & Misc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- ROTA (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Letters to O. Cromwell (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Bampfield; Letter from Paris, 1656 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Misc Transcripts (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Biographical Dictionary of British Radicals in the Seventeenth century, (1982) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Militia (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Stowe MSS. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- B.L. Add. MSS. 34, 011-34, 015 [Visitors to London], 1655 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Bampfield, Letter of. 3/13 Nov. 1688 (MS Carte 70) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Irish in West Indies, Temp. Commonwealth (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Council of State: Messengers, etc. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Council of State, 1649-1660: Attendance (own table) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Commonwealth Council of State (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Dering, Sir Edward. Diary 1656-62. HM 41536 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Sir Philip Warwick (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Misc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- History 244 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Misc. History Seminar Materials (Box 2, Folder 34)
- History 343A. Studies in English History., Fall 1965. (Box 2, Folder 35)
- History 343A. Studies in English History., Fall 1966 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- History 343A. Studies in English History., Spring 1969. (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Free Sheets (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Introduction., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Topics for a Reading Course (Eng. Hist) (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Hist 408c. XVI. Reign of James II (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Hist 408c. XV. Last Years of Charles II. (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Hist 408c. Fine Arts and Belles Lettres (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Introduction to the Bibliography of British History by Charles Mowat (Box 2, Folder 44)
- General Survey of Contemporary Materials (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Catalogs and Resources (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General Survey of Contemporary Materials (I.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Repositories (II) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- General Bibliography (III) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- The State and the Records (IV) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Central Government (V) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Parliament (VI) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Extra materials—Committee of Foreign Affairs, 1667-69 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Academies (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Journals (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Notes on Macaulay (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Const. Hist. 1660-88, Incl. Privy Council (Box 3, Folder 12)
- General Repositories: Introduction (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Unclassified Loose Docs (Box 3, Folder 14)
- PHH Gradebooks, 1947-1981 (Box) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Draft & Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Publication of Town Records by Local Authorities PHH (2nd draft) (Box 3, Folder 17)
- History at VU (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Eyre, William DNB (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Introductions (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Reviews, (1948-1967) (Box 3, Folder 21)
- History at Vanderbilt, (1966) (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Wing R841, 842, Relation. Scotland, 1641 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Letters to Newspapers, V.D. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Amer. Assn. State & Local History (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Phi Alpha Theta Address (Box 3, Folder 26)
- 17th c. mtls in PRD acquired by gift deposit or purchase, (1967) (Box 3, Folder 27)
- James I. (Talk at Men’s Club, Nashv. Presbyn. Church), 27 Apr. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Session on Engl. History, SHA. Richmond, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Planning Study, (1963-64) (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Historical Teaching at Vanderbilt (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Firth’s Cromwell’s Army, (1962) (Box 3, Folder 32)
- County Record Offices, (1962) (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Bibliography of Cromwell, (1961) (1966) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- The 18th Hussars in, 1813 (1961) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Folger Lib. Conference, (1961) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- English Contingent in Portugal, 1662-(1960) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Folger Lib. Conference, (1960) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- The Lane Press (Box 4, Folder 6)
- S.H.A. Session on Stuart England, (1959) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- H. Norwood, (1959) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Clarendon & the University of Oxford (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Unexplored Biographical Resources (Folger Conference), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Bonnet, (1956) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- William Lord Boteler of Brantfield, (1955) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Valentine Greatrakes, (1953) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Humiliation File (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Folger Shakespeare Library Conference on Tudor & Stuart History (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Roman Catholics in Puritan Revolution (SHA), 1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- The End of the Civil War in Devon: Royalist Letter of, 1646 (1953) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Study of Modern History in Britain: European History and American Historians, (1952) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Royalists in Exile (AHA), 1952 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- “Rider”, (1951) (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Anglo-Amer Conf. of Historians (5th), 1951: “Royalists & the Restoration Settlement” (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Home Counties, (1950) (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Waller Letter, (1948) (Box 4, Folder 24)
- William Boteler, (1947) (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Sir John Duncombe, (1947) (Box 4, Folder 26)
- The Eighteenth Century Historians of the Puritan Revolution. Hume and Smollett., 1941 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- The Political Significance of “Absalom and Achitophel”, (1939) (Box 4, Folder 28)
- 1940 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- The Committee of Foreign Affairs, 1667-1679 (1940) (Box 4, Folder 30)
- A Commentary on Thomas Fuller’s Historie of the Holy War (Box 4, Folder 31)
- The Anglican Clergy during the Civil Wars and under the Commonwealth, (1941) (Box 4, Folder 32)
- The Civil War in Yorkshire, (1945) (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Royalist peers during the Puritan Revolution (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Royalists during the Puritan Revolution (Huntington Lib. Seminar), (12 Dec 1940) (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Committee for Foreign Affairs, 1667-9 (1940) (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Roman Catholics during the Puritan Revolution (Box 4, Folder 37)
- 1939 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- The Civil War in Yorkshire, 1642-1646 (1940) (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Gerrard, Richard, (1613-86) (Box 4, Folder 41)
- New DNB article; Gerrard, Richard, (1613-1686) (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Genties, Ian—Promotion, (1992) (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Corrections to DNB (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Economic (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Williams, Andrew. C.C. Privateer. John (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Literature and the English Civil War, ed. Healy & Sawday, (1990) (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Bill of Rights (Huntington Docents), 29 Apr. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Wharton Family (Kent Clark) (Box 4, Folder 49)
- “The Experience of the Civil War: PCCBS, March 30, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Numbering the Civil War: Armies before the New model, (28 Jan 1988) (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Beefeaters (Box 4, Folder 52)
- The Original Officer List of the New Model Army,” ed. Robert K.G. Temple, BIHR, LIX, no. 139 (May 1986, 50-77: Index) (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Kirke (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Pricket, Robert, (1987) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Armstrong, J., (1986) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Cornet, Edmund Nangle (d. 1666), [July 1986] (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Loftis, John. MS. Critique, (1984) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Merrick, ed. Early Modern European History, (1983) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Bridges, (1983) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Bridges (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Patronage and Place in the Chancery under Lord Bacon, (1982) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Review of Childs. The Army, James II, and the Glorious Revolution (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Journal of Church and State (Box 5, Folder 11)
- James Howell; paper on, reviewed for the Historian. Eval, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Eaves, Richard Glen (Auburn U) Evaluation, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Review of A. Miller Grenville, (1980) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- H.E. Huntington (Freolac Club), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Solt, Leo. Paper on Fielder (1979-81). Critique. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Review of Sherwood. Court of O. Cromwell (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Carolina’s symposium bibliography, (1979) (Box 5, Folder 18)
- The American Revolution from the English Point of View (S.A.R), 15 March 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- M. Kishlansky “Army & Levellers.” Critique, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Elton. Annual bibliog.., (1978) (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Rev. Carlson Festschrift, (1977) (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Forum Press: Textbook in English History. Critique, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Local Politics during the Puritan Revolution, (1977) (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Rev. 1976. Hill, Change & Continuity (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Clarendon, Sir R. Howard, & Chancery Office-Holding, (1975) (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Shakespeare’s London: Freolac Club, Apr 7, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Review: Holmes, the Eastern Association, (1974) (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Cromwell, A Profile, (1973) (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Northern Irish Struggle: (Freolac), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Plumb, J.H. Introduction., 8 Mar 1972 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Southern Historical Association: Session on British History, 1973 (Commentator) (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Burton’s diary; Johnson reprint, (1974) (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Hardacre: Index of Speakers in the Parliament of 1659. First draft w/ letters, (1971) (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Burton’s Diary: Individual Speakers (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Burton’s Diary (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Burton’s Diary, Purchase of Film (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Local History societies (JUL) (Box 5, Folder 38)
- The Intro. Course (Tenn Hist. Conf), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Review: Rowe, Sir Henry Vane, (1970) (Box 5, Folder 40)
- The Reformation and the art of giving, (1970) (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Sachse, W. L., Bibliographic Handbook, England 1660-89. Critique, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Sachse Sourcebk. Critique, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Bridgeman Letter, 1663, (1969) (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Rev.—Jones, Middleton, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- A (Miscellaneous) (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Abernathy, George R. (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Auffenberg, Thomas L. (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Aylmer, Gerald E. (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Blumenthal, Uta-Renate (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Boorman, Howard L. (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Baxter, Richard R. (Box 5, Folder 52)
- B (Miscellaneous) (Box 5, Folder 53)
- C (Miscellaneous) (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Carlson, Leland H. (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Clark, Peter (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Carpenter, Jr., Edwin H. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Carpenter, Jr., Edwin H., Diary (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cope, Esther S. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Delzell, Charles F. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Fleming, N. Bond (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Fox, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Freedman, Paul (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Fulbright association (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Galbraith, Vivian & Georgina (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Grantham, Dewey W. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Griffiths, David & Joan (Box 6, Folder 11)
- G (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Griffiths, Philip & Joyce (Box 6, Folder 13)
- H (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Hayner, Linda K. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Henderson, Frances (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Hollis, Daniel W. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Kenyon, John P. (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Offprints, P.H.H. (Box 6, Folder 19)
- K (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Lane, Alexander (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Laurence, Anne (Box 6, Folder 22)
- L (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Lutaud, Oliver (Box 6, Folder 24)
- M (misc) (Box 6, Folder 25)
- McSeveney, Samuel T. (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Marzahl, Reter (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Morris, Patricia Ann (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Mullins, E.L.C. (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Neville, John D. (Box 6, Folder 30)
- N (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Ohlmeyer, Jane (Box 6, Folder 32)
- O (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Pinckney, Paul J. (Box 6, Folder 34)
- P (Misc) (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Phillips, Dayton (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Pasadena Historical Society Committee Meetings (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Richardson, Roger C. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Robinson, Thos (Box 7, Folder 3)
- R (Misc) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Stedman, John (Box 7, Folder 5)
- T (Misc) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Temple, Robert K.G. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Underdown (Box 7, Folder 8)
- V (Misc) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Weaver, Herbert (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Wright, Louis B. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- W (Misc) (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Woolrych, Austin (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondece—Wikelund (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Bloopers (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Unclassified material (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Notes (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Books & MSS (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Universities (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Unclassified but relevant news clippings-2 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Unclassified but relevant news clippings-1 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Conference Materials (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Conference Materials (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Roanoke Voyages (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Footwear in the British Army (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Hist 242.II. Historiography and Materials. (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Cummings, Charles F. English Architecture, 1640-1660 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Hist 242. XIX. The Professions. (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Hist 242. The Universities (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Hist 243. The Legacy of the Puritan Revolution (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Hist 243. The Triumph of the Anglican Church (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Hist 243 XXXV. The Restoration Settlement (Box 7, Folder 33)
- History 343., Spring 1959 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- History 343., Spring 1961 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- History 343., Spring 1962 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- History 343., Fall 1962 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- History 343., Fall 1964 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- History 343., Fall 1977 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- History 343a. Introduction. (Box 7, Folder 40)
- History 343a. Individual histories. (Box 7, Folder 41)
- History 343a. The armed forces (Box 7, Folder 42)
- History 343a. Economic history (Box 7, Folder 43)
- History 343a. Science (Box 7, Folder 44)
- History 343a. Constitutional History (Box 7, Folder 45)
- History 343a. Religious history (Box 7, Folder 46)
- History 343a. Literature and philosophy (Box 7, Folder 47)
- History 343a. Contemporary writers (Box 7, Folder 48)
- History 343a. Education (Box 7, Folder 49)
- History 343a. Foreign relations (Box 7, Folder 50)
- History 343a. Dissenters (Box 7, Folder 51)
- History 343a. XVIII.c.compilers (Box 7, Folder 52)
- History 343a. Parliament & parties (Box 7, Folder 53)
- History 343a. Central government (Box 7, Folder 54)
- History 343a. Church of England (Box 7, Folder 55)
- History 343a. Local government (Box 7, Folder 56)
- History 343a. XVII.c.writers (Box 7, Folder 57)
- History 343a. XIX.-XX.c.writers (Box 7, Folder 58)
- History 343a. Social history (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Inter-office correspondence (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Class roll, 1/30/70 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- History 504 Seminar (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Syllabi (Box 7, Folder 63)
- History 243 (Box 7, Folder 64)
- History 246., Spring semester 1981 (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Cross, Charles W. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Fox, George T. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Markham, C. Bibliog. Wm Perkins (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Melton, Frank T. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Opper, Mary (Mrs.) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Pinckney, Paul J. Suffolk elections (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Strock, Nancy (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Strickland, W. Bibliog of J. Goodwin (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Smith, Steven R. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Shouse, Sarah N. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- References (Box 9, Folder 11)
- V.U. Biographical Data Sheets (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Vanderbilt University: Appointment & Salary, 1947-81 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- VU. Enrollments, Work Effort Repts. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- VU Student Government Assn. Course Evaluations (Box 9, Folder 15)
- List of Classes Taught, 1947-81 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- VU: Graduate Work & Independent Study (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Folger Library Grant, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Fulbright Grant U.K.—, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Guggenheim Grant, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- N.E.H. Stipend, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Amer. Counc. Of Learned Societies. Grant, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- VU—Leave, Fall 1979 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- VU. Univ. Research Council Grants (Box 9, Folder 24)
- VU Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 25)
- List and Index Society (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Public Record Office (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Essay draft (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Notes (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Maps (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Maps (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Godfrey Davies offprints 1 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Godfrey Davies offprints 2 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Godfrey Davies offprints 3 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- DNB (Biographical Index Cards A-H) (Box) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- DNB (Biographical Index Cards I-Z) (Box) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Historical Association leaflets (29, 46, 52, 54, 55, 57, 61, 64, 128) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Historical Association leaflets (66-67, 70, 75, 77, 79, 84, 87, 89) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Historical Association leaflets (90, 93-95, 99-101) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Historical Association leaflets (102-107, 109-111) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Historical Association leaflets (112, 114, 118-120, 124-125) and related materials (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Vanderbilt (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Research (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Notes (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Social and Economic History of Wiltshire, 1540-1640 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Teaching History (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Micellaneous (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Ireland (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Establishment (Box 11, Folder 11)
- History of Irish Standing Army (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Straford’s Army (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 15)
- E.S.T-F.T.B (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Bampfield (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Royal Hist. Society (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Hyde Family of Cheshire (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Pinkney (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Chantries (Box 11, Folder 23)
- British Studies Mercury (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Patronage and Purchase in the Irish Standing Army under Thomas Wentworth., 1989 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Davies Bibliography Supplement (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Bibliography (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Maps (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Genesis of the Declaration of Breda, 1657-1660 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Own Reviews (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Dept of History Publications & Miscellaneous Materials (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Vanderbilt Publications & Miscellaneous Materials (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Vanderbilt Publications and History Dept. Publications (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Vanderbilt Publications (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Dept. of History Newsletters (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Materials sent to Vanderbilt (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Brearly, Samuel (Box 11, Folder 38)
- Works in Progress (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Melton, Frank T., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Fox, Tom (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Lauderdale Papers Ed. Morris (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Strickland, Bill (Box 11, Folder 43)
- McGrath, Eileen Lucy. (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Baringer, James Edward. (Box 11, Folder 45)
- Smith, William A. (Box 11, Folder 46)
- MacFarland, Perre. (Box 11, Folder 47)
- Primavera, Gary T. (Box 11, Folder 48)
- Martin, Mary Elizabeth (Box 11, Folder 49)
- Smith, Steven R. (Box 11, Folder 50)
- Morris, Patricia Ann. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Calgano, Michael James. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Henry, Lawrence Carl (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Ekrut, Vernon Stanley (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Auffenberg, Thomas Lynn (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Neville, John Davenport (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Hayner, Linda (Box 12, Folder 7)